# James Guo

# Senior Full Stack Engineer

jg.dreamjg01@gmail.com • https://bitwhiz05.github.io/ • Wroclaw, Poland

# Summary

James is a senior software engineer with a demonstrated history of working in various industries, including eCommerce, finance, telecommunications, healthcare, and many others. His experience with full-lifecycle work across multiple fields makes him a valuable asset to any team. He also gained valuable experience working with startups, launching new projects from scratch. He has a deep understanding of both front-end and back-end technologies. He is a fast learner with a passion for technology and innovation.

## Experience

#### Simform

### Senior Software Engineer

06/2022 - 10/2024

- Developed and maintained high-quality software by adding features, fixing bugs, and writing unit and e2e tests to ensure robust code and system functionality.
- Made crucial decisions regarding tech stack and system design that had a significant impact on the success
  of the product.
- Designed and developed high-performance backend systems using Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, PHP (Laravel, Symfony), Python (Django, Flask, FastAPI), and various Java, C#, Go, and Rust frameworks.
- Created scalable frontend systems with JavaScript/TypeScript frameworks: React, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Angular, and Svelte, ensuring seamless backend integration.
- Led development and provided technical guidance on Ethereum and Solana projects, focusing on smart contracts, DApps, NFTs, and Web3 integrations.
- Built cross-platform mobile apps using React Native, Flutter, and Java/Kotlin for Android, as well as Swift for iOS.
- Leveraged serverless architecture and AWS Cloud services (Lambda, DynamoDB, RDS, API Gateway, Cognito, EC2, ECS, EKS, S3, etc.) for scalability.
- Led a team of 5 people in Agile development work, coordinating tasks and ensuring timely delivery of highquality software solutions.

## Gigatron

#### Senior Full Stack Engineer

05/2021 - 05/2022

- Revamped an outdated legacy PHP application to a Vue.js and Django-based app, boosting performance by 50%.
- Led the development of an admin and enterprise web portal, optimizing modules and resolving bugs in the feature-rich eCommerce platform.
- Integrated third-party APIs for payment gateways like PayPal and Stripe, and set up email and SMS services with Sendgrid, Twilio, and AWS SES.
- · Conducted system performance analysis and optimization to enhance scalability, reliability, and security.
- Collaborated with team members, responsible for technical decisions and reviewing others' work.

#### **Prevess**

Full Stack Engineer 05/2020 – 04/2021

 Spearheaded the development of an Al-powered healthcare platform to analyze health data and deliver customized nutrition plans.

- Developed the front and back end with React, Django, LLM, LangChain, PostgreSQL, and AWS.
- Utilized secure APIs and interoperability standards to ensure smooth integration with healthcare systems and electronic health records.
- Conducted code reviews and collaborated on developing reusable and sustainable solutions.

#### Andersen Lab

Full Stack Engineer

- Reviewed multiple existing web pages, programs and mobile apps to locate and fix bugs and implement enhancements to improve speed and functionality.
- Adopted engineering best practices and delivered the highest quality scalable solutions.
- Involved in Requirements gathering, Analysis, Design, Development, and Testing of the application in Agile Scrum.
- Documented all supported systems and applications to effectively train the new and existing team members.

#### Andersen Lab

Web Developer 08/2016 – 03/2018

- Worked on the multiple software projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from design to implementation and delivery.
- Tested and updated existing software and using own knowledge and expertise made improvement suggestions.
- · Transformed design mock-ups into pixel-perfect and mobile responsive layouts.
- · Learned multiple threading, concurrency, design patterns, and their impacts on application concurrency.

#### Education

# Lublin University of Technology

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science

2012 - 2016

03/2018 - 04/2020

#### Skills

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Kotlin, PHP, Python, C#, Go, Rust, Solidity

Frontend: React, React Native, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Angular, Svelte, D3.js, Chart.js, Three.js, WebGL

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, Nest.js, Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Django, Flask, FastAPI, ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, Blazor, Gin, Fiber, Rocket, Laravel, Symfony

Blockchain & Dapps: Web3.js, Ethers.js, Ethereum, Solana, ERC20 Tokens, NFTs, Staking, DEX, Farming

Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Firebase

Cloud & DevOps: AWS, GCP, Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, Jenkins

AI/ML & LLM: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, LangChain, OpenAl API

Testing: Jest, Mocha, Cypress, pytest, JUnit, PHPUnit, Hardhat, Foundry, Truffle, Remix